

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, GAME ENGINE & GAMEPLAY DEVELOPER

Details

Barcelona
Spain
+34 671 11 62 23
magalenyo7@gmail.com

Links

miguelangelbuenorivera.com

LinkedIn

Github (@magalenyo)

Shutdown (video game)

Boundead (video game)

Skills

Java, C++, C#, Angular, NodeJS

Springboot, JPA, Liquibase

MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

SVN and Git (Github and BitBucket)

Continuos integration with Jenkins

OpenGL, GLSL

Languages

Spanish (Native)

Catalan (Native)

English (Fluent - B2 Certificate)

Profile

I'm a 26 years old passionate, curious, and openminded programmer that seeks not only to grow as a professional, but as a person as well.

3+ years experience as a Full Stack developer for different consulting companies, working with agile methodologies, developing websites, internal tools and services with **Angular** and **Java Springboot**. I have also had the chance to occasionally manage small teams of 2-4 people, doing project planning, technical and functional documents, estimations and test plans tasks.

My main interests are full stack development, video game engine programming, gameplay programming, graphics, VFX and 3D Modelling.

Employment History

Full Stack Developer, Next Digital, Madrid (remote)

SEPTEMBER 2022 - PRESENT

Currently working for **Iberia Airlines**, developing a multi-platform smartphone application to manage internal systems with Angular (Ionic) and Java Spring Boot. Also developing core services based on Java Springboot.

Solutions Analyst, NTT Data Europe & Latam, Barcelona

SEPTEMBER 2019 - JULY 2022

Working with Agile methodologies like Scrum (+Kanban and Jira), and SVN and Git (Github) in the following projects:

- Development of Allianz Insurance websites and internal tools.
 - Programming: full stack development of an insurance policy contract site and the development of an internal UI Editor tool to create Workflows.
 Both projects were developed in Angular and Java Springboot.
- Development and maintenance of **Zurich Insurance** customers' web portal.
 - Projects development: task estimation, team organization, creation of technical and functional documents, creation of requirements documents.
 - Programming: full stack development of the client's site with a custom framework based on Java, HTML, CSS and JS.

Programmer, EUTI Software, Girona

FEBRUARY 2019 - JUNE 2019

Development and publishing of an application for Android and iOS made with Xamarin.Forms (C#) and maintenance of a server made in Visual Basic.

Education

Master's Degree in Advanced Programming for AAA Video Games, Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC), Barcelona

OCTOBER 2020 - NOVEMBER 2021

In the master's degree we learned about the foundations of video game engines and the creation process of a video game from start to finish. The final project was made as a team, and some of my work was:

- Development of a 3D game engine programmed in C++ and OpenGL. <u>Engine</u> repository.
 - Graphics: UI Shaders, Dissolve Shader (Simplex Noise Map), Chromatic Aberration, MSAA integration.
 - UI Components used in scenes: 2D Transform, Text, Image and others.
 - Navigation Module: integration of Recast & Detour libraries for the creation of NavMesh, NavAgent and NavObstacle.
- Development of a 3D video game in C++. <u>Game trailer</u> and <u>Full gameplay</u>. <u>Video game repository</u>.
 - Scene creation and management: management of the different scenes of our video game; main menu, level 1, level 2, boss level, pause menu, death screen.
 - Gameplay: Final Boss bullet hell fully customizable (easy to change parameters to create additional new patterns), UI scripts and animations, scripts for simple behaviors.
- Other: gameplay team lead in last sprints; assisting the producers in the team organization and managing the developers of the gameplay team, general bugs solving.

B.S. in Computer Engineering, Universitat de Girona (UDG), Girona

SEPTEMBER 2014 - JULY 2019

Specialized in Software Engineering.

Boundead: as a final project, a colleague and I developed a 2.5D action/platform video game made in Unity (C#).

To check the gameplay, access the <u>Youtube Playlist</u> and check the source code <u>here</u>. To play it yourself, <u>download the project</u>.